Álan Crístoffer e Sousa



Personal Data 31 years old, Brazilian

Contact +55 (37) 999971514

acristoffers@gmail.com https://acristoffers.me

Languages

Portuguese (native) English (C1) German (C1) French (B1)

Skills

System Analysis and Control, C/C++, Python, Kotlin, Assembly, MATLAB, Android Development, Frontend, Backend, Embedded, Automation, Robotics

Summary

PhD Student and **Master of Science** in Electrical Engineering, in the field of **Control Theory**, and **Mechatronic Engineer** with experience in **system analysis and control** and **programming**. Has worked in two scientific initiations building a platform that interfaces with hardware for system analysis and control objectives and learning Model Predictive Control.

Experience

2016–2016 Acal BFi Dietzenbach, Hessen, Germany

Intern

During this internship, I developed a platform to measure the power loss inside

the kernel of the inductor used in a PFC circuit.

2010–2013 **Corpo de Bombeiros Militar de Minas Gerais** Divinópolis, Minas Gerais, Brazil

Soldier

As a firefighter I was entitled to work as a first-aider and diver, being the first response in all sorts of accidents, from fire in the wilds to car accidents and

industrial and natural disasters.

Education

2021 – Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering Université de Reims Champagne-Ardene

I'm working on attack detection and mitigation on cyber-physical systems.

2020–2020 Master in Electrical Engineering CEFET-MG/UFSJ

I developed a switching-rule for constrained switched systems based on Region of Attraction under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Valter Leite and co-supervision of Prof. Dr.

Walter Lucia.

2013–2019 **Mechatronic Engineering** Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica de Minas Gerais

Since my first semester, I helped other students from graduation, master and PhD. with their projects, especially with programming. In my last year, I became the student

representative in the Graduation Council

2015–2016 **Student Exchange** Frankfurt University of Applied Sciences, Germany

I studied as an exchange student through the Brazilian government's program Ciências

Sem Fronteiras (Science Without Borders).

2015–2015 **Student Exchange** Université Grenoble Alpes, France

I studied as an exchange student through the partnership between UGA and CEFET-MG. There I worked in the robotics laboratory helping the team which won the second

place in the National Instruments MyRIO Paris competition.

Extracurricular

2019

2014

Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'Control of a coupled tanks system'. 2019 Cosupervised Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'Modelling of an oven with spacedistributed parameters'. 2018 BIC-Jr Cosupervised Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'System modelling for process controľ. 2017 & 2018 Python mini-course Ministered I ministered a Python mini-course at my university. The textbook (in Portuguese) is freely available at https://acristoffers.me/Python3.pdf 2017 Semana C&T - Week of Science and Technology 1st Place My project got the first place in the 13rd workshop at my university. 2015 **National Instruments MyRIO Compatition, Paris** 2nd Place I helped the team that got the second place in the competition. I was responsible for

the code interfacing with the camera and recognizing colors.

Latin American Robotics Competition 3rd Place

Cosupervised

I was part of the team that got the third place in the competition. I was responsible for

the circuitry and programming of one of the robots.

Publications

2020 E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; SILVA, LUÍS F. P.; LUCIA, WALTER; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S. (2020). XXIII Congresso Brasileiro de Automática: Command Governor strategy based on region of attraction control switching. 2020 FILHO, MARCIO R. O.; E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S.; COSTA, EMERSON S. (2020). XLI CILAMCE: Control Of An Oven With Space-Distributed Sensors. FILHO, MARCIO R. O.; E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; COSTA, EMERSON S.; LEITE, VALTER J. DE 2019 S. (2019). XL IBERO-LATIN AMERICAN CONGRESS ON COMPUTATIONAL METHODS IN **ENGINEERING: Prototype Modelling for Real Systems.** E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; LEITE, VALTER J. S.; RUBIO SCOLA, IGNACIO. Affordable Control 2018 Platform with MPC Application. Studies in Informatics and Control, v. 27, p. 265-274, 2018. 2017

LOPES, A. N. D.; LEITE, V. J. S.; SILVA, L. F. P.; e Sousa, Álan. ESTABILIZAÇÃO LOCAL DE SISTEMAS NÃO-LINEARES VIA MODELAGEM FUZZY TAKAGI-SUGENO DISCRETA NO TEMPO. In: Simpósio Brasileiro de Automação Inteligente (SBAI), 2017, Porto Alegre -RS. XIII Simpósio Brasileiro de Automação Inteligente, 2017.

Interests

System Analysis and Control Theory I worked with constrained switched systems and MPC. I studied non-linear and robust control, positive polynomials in control and complex networks.

Programming C/C++, Python, Julia, Kotlin, Rust, Ruby, MATLAB...Languages are just tools in the belt. I can program using structured, object oriented and functional paradigms. I always try to use design patterns to make the code more organized and maintainable.